{"tossups": [{"question": "The Sicilian Vespers helped prevent one of these events from occurring by burning the ships of Charles of Anjou in Messina harbor. The use of Greek Fire in the Bosphorus strait helped stop one of these events. A successful one of these events saw Orban design the massive Dardanelles cannon at the behest of Mehmed II. One of the most well known of these events was ordered by Enrico Dandolo during the Fourth Crusade. For ten points, name these events that involve looting the capitol of the Byzantine Empire.", "answer": "<b> sacks of Constantinople</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man claimed to use a hand-pumped rail car to scout for trains while on an unapproved mission in Veracruz. This general neutralized Raubal in his direction of Operation Cartwheel, a year after an invasion on the Lingayen Gulf forced his retreat to Corregidor. Six months after the Wake Island Conference, this man was dismissed from command of a war in which he organized the Inchon landing. For ten points, name this commander of U.N. forces during the Korean War, who proclaimed \u201cI shall return\u201d to the Philippines during World War II.", "answer": "Douglas<b> MacArthur</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The ruling in this case overruled an appelate ruling that found that the \u201cConstitution is silent on the subject,\u201d thereby protecting the implied power of Congress to carry out constitutional laws by \u201cnecessary and proper\u201d means. Chief Justice John Marshall noted that \u201cthe power to tax involves the power to destroy\u201d in his unanimous decision in, for ten points, what 1819 Supreme Court case lodged against the Bank of the United States by the state of Maryland?", "answer": "<b> McCulloch</b> v. Maryland", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The Mongols supposedly filled nine sacks with these objects after defeating Henry the Pious of Silesia at Legnica. During the Vietnam War, 101st Airborne\u2019s Tiger Force unit was accused of creating necklaces out of these objects. James Oglethorpe led troops at the battles of Gully Hole Creek and Bloody Marsh in a war named for one of these objects lost by a smuggler; after three years, that war became a part of the larger War of the Austrian Succession. Robert Jenkins lost, for ten points, what body part?", "answer": "severed<b> ear</b>s (accept (War of)<b> Jenkins\u2019 Ear</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "During this event, a comparison to David and Jonathan was used to answer the question \u201cWhat is the\u2018love that dare not speak its name?\u2019\u201d This event was triggered by the Marquess of Queensbury\u2019s victory in a libel suit. In its aftermath, its subject wrote a 50,000 word letter to \u201cBosie\u201d while serving a sentence of hard labor at Reading Gaol [redding jail]. For ten points, name this 1895 event in which the author of<em> The Picture of Dorian Gray</em> and<em> The Importance of Being Earnest</em> was convicted of inappropriate relations with Lord Alfred Douglas.", "answer": "the<b> trial</b> of Oscar<b> Wilde</b> for<b> homosexuality</b> (or<b> Regina v. Wilde</b>; accept descriptions of Oscar<b> Wilde</b> being<b> arrested</b> and/or<b> charged</b> for<b> homosexual</b> behavior, gross<b> indecency</b> and/or <b>sodomy</b>; accept<b> imprisonment</b> of Oscar<b> Wilde</b>; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "One leader of this organization sued William Havemeyer for libel; Havemeyer died on the day of that trial. This organization, led by \u201cHonest\u201d John Kelly, faded away shortly after the fall of Carmine DiSapio. The first Catholic nominee for president, Al Smith, was strongly backed by this organization, which was developed by Aaron Burr but lost influence during Franklin D. Roosevelt\u2019s governorship. Thomas Nast depicted this group as a tiger devouring democracy in 1871. Boss Tweed led, for ten points, what New York political machine?", "answer": "<b> Tammany Hall</b> (accept<b> Society of St. Tammany</b> or<b> Sons of St. Tammany</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this communist ruler of Yugoslavia and guerrilla leader during World War II.", "answer": "<b> Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee</b> (or<b> SNCC</b> [\u201dsnick\u201d]; accept<b> Student National Coordinating Committee</b>) (8) This man, who tried Archbishop Aloysius Stepinac for collaborating with the Nazis, led the only Eastern European nation that accepted aid from the ECA. He defeated Chetnik leader Draa Mihailovic [mee-hail-oh-vitch] before reaching his highest office. This man\u2019s country was kicked out of COMINFORM after his feud with Stalin led to a break with the USSR in 1949. For ten points, name this communist ruler of Yugoslavia and guerrilla leader during World War II. ANSWER: Josip Broz<b> Tito</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This party negotiated with Adolph Joffe for aid on the condition that this party allied itself with a rival; that alliance ended in the April 12th incident. The confiscation of contraband cigarettes from a 40 year old widow sparked the 2-28 (+) massacre carried out</b> <b>by this party.</b> <b>In January 2016, this party lost a presidential election to the Democratic</b> <b>Progressive Party\u2019s candidate Tsai Ing-Wen. This party was founded shortly after the (*) </b>Xinhai Revolution by Song Jiaoren and Sun Yat-Sen. For ten points, name this Taiwanese political party, founded in 1911 in China by Chiang Kai-Shek.", "answer": "<b> Kuomintang</b> (or<b> KMT</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "\u201cPersonal liberty laws\u201d were meant to circumvent these laws, which were invalidated by the (*)</b> 13th Amendment. For ten points, identify these laws, one of which was also passed in 1850, which stated that certain property could be returned to its owners after escape into a free state.", "answer": "<b> Fugitive Slave Law</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Dr. Eric Lander, who published a controversial revisionist history of the development of CRISPR [\u201dcrisper\u201d] DNA segments in January 2015, directs the (+) Broad</b> <b>Institute, a collaboration between these two schools.</b> <b>These schools also collaborate in a</b> <b>Masters\u2019 program between one\u2019s Sloan School of Management and the other\u2019s (*)</b> Kennedy School of Government. For ten points, name these two universities, both located on the north side of the Charles River in Cambridge, Massachusetts.", "answer": "<b> Harvard</b> University<b> and Massachusetts Institute of Technology</b> (or<b> MIT</b>; accept in either order; prompt if only one is given)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>This man wrote that \u201cThe \u2018power to regulate commerce among the several States\u2019cannot include a power to construct roads and canals\u201d in his veto of the Bonus Bill. Macon\u2019s (+) Bills were passed under this President, repealing the Non-Intercourse Act. The charter for the first Bank of the United States expired under this man; five years later, he launched the (*) </b> Second Bank of the United States to help finance the rebuilding efforts after the War of 1812. For ten points, name this founding father who preceded James Monroe as U.S. President.", "answer": "James<b> Madison</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A 28-volume work on this subject opened with the call to sell your townhouse and give up the household gods of the city; that work was written in Punic by Mago. In another work, the author teaches this subject to his squanderous brother (+) Perses. The \u201cworks\u201dof Hesiod\u2019s</b><em><b> Works and Days</b></em><b> details how to be successful at this practice, which Cincinnatus (*)</b> resumed after his dictatorships. For ten points, name this practice which includes animal husbandry, beekeeping, and the cultivation of crops for food.", "answer": "<b> agriculture</b> or<b> farm</b>ing (accept equivalents; accept any specific form, such as<b> beekeeping</b> or <b>making wine</b>) <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}